[{"id": "59e6b752fb6c85e9e634ff4b", "question": "What does \"Rx\" mean to a pharmacist?", "answer": "A medical prescription", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339738", "question": "What is the number of the house \"The Simpsons\" live in at Evergreen Terrace, Springfield?", "answer": "742", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f544ff048f679a45aad4", "question": "Ombrophobia fear of what?", "answer": "Rain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6690fa5bfecdd737e0876", "question": "What is the alternative name of \"Rock, Paper, Scissors\"?", "answer": "Roshambo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a28f", "question": "What was Cat Stevens' birth name?", "answer": "Steven Demetre Georgiou", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ed3", "question": "In what 1952 play is Giles Corey \"pressed\" to death, his last words being \"More weight\"?", "answer": "The Crucible", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a162a1bf01ec323f8491721", "question": "What novel by Geoffrey Household was about an attempt to kill Hitler?", "answer": "Rogue Male", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b821e662d71a5365101d", "question": "What do \"Peter Pan\" author J.M. Barrie's initials stand for?", "answer": "James Matthew", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feb33fd7e83c707845b20c7", "question": "What actor said, \"If you had been a public figure since the time you were a toddler\u2026 maybe you too would value privacy above all else\"?", "answer": "Jodie Foster", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede4226ce05a3942286dd8", "question": "What was the name of the 1976 Led Zeppelin concert film?", "answer": "The Song Remains the Same", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ded29aea2747c8aff16d3f", "question": "Vermicelli pasta literally translates as what in Italian?", "answer": "Little worms", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada4", "question": "In what US state was the outlaw Jesse James born?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339802", "question": "What major does David Bowie's \"Space Oddity\" refer to?", "answer": "Major Tom", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8a60ec223966ae8f8830", "question": "What is the only videogame franchise originating in the 1970's to have thus far generated over $1 billion in revenue?", "answer": "Space Invaders", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c810", "question": "A deficiency of which vitamin can lead to night blindness?", "answer": "A", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2d4042596a59cbdfbd3a0", "question": "What do websites use to remember your preferences?", "answer": "Cookies", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc06", "question": "A crusiverbalist is someone who is skilled at what?", "answer": "The creation or solving of crosswords", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c90e", "question": "What is the name of the distance around the outside of a circle?", "answer": "Circumference", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7cb5e877e98cb97778a18", "question": "In what year was the former republic of Czechoslovakia formed?", "answer": "1918", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b653", "question": "On the classic Monopoly board, which property has a misspelled name?", "answer": "Marvin Gardens", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a0a", "question": "What are bongo drums traditionally held between for playing?", "answer": "The knees", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febd8a87e83c707845b2177", "question": "Who is the only prison inmate to admit that he is guilty in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8c32ec223966ae8f8847", "question": "Complete the quote \"I have to remind myself that some birds aren't meant to be\u2026\" from the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "\"Caged\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392f6", "question": "In the movie \"Goodfellas\", who played the role of Henry Hill?", "answer": "Ray Liotta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7d8", "question": "What two authors' characters are used to name the moon of Uranus?", "answer": "William Shakespeare and Alexander Pope", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdc0e7d469bb8041d07a060", "question": "When a chef puts out every ingredient needed to prepare a dish ahead of time, what is it called?", "answer": "Mise En Place", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a787", "question": "What important crop is the Rhine Valley in Germany known for growing?", "answer": "Grapes", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6bf", "question": "Which Amendment to the Constitution of the United States guarantees the right to a speedy trial?", "answer": "Sixth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cfb", "question": "What is the dot on the letter i named?", "answer": "A tittle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6007820ebd51d85e222ab652", "question": "What object commonly appears in Picasso's paintings?", "answer": "Guitars (Although his Cubist works approach abstraction, he never relinquished the objects of the real world as subject matter.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ded0acea2747c8aff16d2b", "question": "Tin is primarily obtained from which ore?", "answer": "Cassiterite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389d4", "question": "Who spent a month in jail for insubordinate behavior - Johann Sebastian Bach or Jerry Lee Lewis?", "answer": "Johann Sebastian Bach", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338992", "question": "How old is the teenage lead character at the end of the book \"Anne of Green Gables\"?", "answer": "16", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133946f", "question": "What was Toula's wedding present from her parents in the movie \"My Big Fat Greek Wedding\"?", "answer": "A house", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a994761d1b4d384d5d698", "question": "Who played the role of Quint Asper in the TV show \"Gunsmoke\"?", "answer": "Burt Reynolds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c18", "question": "Who created the TV show \"SpongeBob SquarePants\"?", "answer": "Stephen Hillenburg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6bac8fb6c85e9e634ff52", "question": "What is the name for the group of men who elect a Pope?", "answer": "College of Cardinals", "category": "general"}, {"id": "592eb0f6f83302ff91e464a2", "question": "What company makes the Vince Lombardi Trophy?", "answer": "Tiffany & Co.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdfb91b003d27d341092bc1", "question": "How many Smithsonian museums and galleries are in Washington, D.C.?", "answer": "17", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f168e3f7c52aae91cc07cb", "question": "What is the core in most pencils made from?", "answer": "Graphite", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0a4", "question": "What queen was ordered beheaded by her cousin, Elizabeth I?", "answer": "Mary, Queen of Scots", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad73", "question": "Where was the first US Mint constructed?", "answer": "Philadelphia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c3e99c4ebfabb9c85d8a975", "question": "Which modern musical instrument evolved from the \"Sackbut\"?", "answer": "The Trombone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b118", "question": "In ancient Japan, all people who gave massages had to be what?", "answer": "Blind", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5989ac05cb8751d53e7d7608", "question": "\"Speak, Memory\" is an autobiographical memoir by which Russian author?", "answer": "Vladimir Nabokov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133982c", "question": "What town was the setting of The Andy Griffith Show?", "answer": "Mayberry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59068132ff9c0647b50a8092", "question": "Who plays the role of Elliot Alderson in the TV show \"Mr. Robot\"?", "answer": "Rami Malek", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd69f9a6c0f9723ab15cb2c", "question": "What was Mahatma Gandhi's profession?", "answer": "Lawyer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6f7", "question": "What is the name of the process of splitting atomic nuclei?", "answer": "Fission", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab45", "question": "What is the capital of Somalia?", "answer": "Mogadishu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d3c", "question": "What \"Animal House\" actor made his show-biz debut as the voice of TV's Jonny Quest?", "answer": "Tim Matheson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef96c96ce05a3942286ea1", "question": "Which martial art does Miss Piggy practice?", "answer": "Karate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab99bbc21a8909e5c332d2f", "question": "What novel was the 1988 film \"Who Framed Roger Rabbit\" loosely based on?", "answer": "Who Censored Roger Rabbit?", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa92", "question": "Nashville is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133992f", "question": "What was Van Halen\u2019s first, and only #1 hit on the US Billboard singles chart?", "answer": "Jump", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bb357722627b8fe95581be4", "question": "Brisbane is the capital of which Australian state?", "answer": "Queensland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab40", "question": "What place is also known as \"land nearest nowhere\"?", "answer": "Cape Three Points", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9a7", "question": "What is the technical term for armpit?", "answer": "Axilla", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d4", "question": "What is the largest island in the Mediterranean Sea?", "answer": "Sicily", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfb2", "question": "Macrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Long waits", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae97", "question": "To what tribe did Sitting Bull belong?", "answer": "Sioux", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c13a", "question": "How many squares are there on a chessboard?", "answer": "64", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ad", "question": "Which rock star plays the role of vampire in the 1983 movie \"The Hunger\"?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc8", "question": "Which country gave us the dish Cullen Skink?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbeb", "question": "What year saw Jean Paul Gaultier's first individual collection for women?", "answer": "1976", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ef0", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Willy Loman?", "answer": "Death of a Salesman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be4f", "question": "In 2005, what product reintroduced its catchphrase \"I can't believe I ate the whole thing\"?", "answer": "Alka-Seltzer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a609", "question": "In which European country is the resort town of Spa?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab1884baab681b0929218b", "question": "Which company introduced the Mangusta in the 1960\u2019s?", "answer": "De Tomaso", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be31", "question": "How many players are there in a standard beach volleyball team?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071c213745b36be73039c8", "question": "How many children does Tony have in the comic series \"Chew\"?", "answer": "One", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b440", "question": "Who was the 32nd President of the United States?", "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59cdb4fa65ff7d326b622a8b", "question": "In which Shakespearean play would we see the character of Aaron?", "answer": "Titus Andronicus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c023", "question": "In what city was fashion designer Gianni Versace killed?", "answer": "Miami Beach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c6a", "question": "What movie helped popularize disco music worldwide?", "answer": "Saturday Night Fever", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a422", "question": "What is the capital of New Zealand?", "answer": "Wellington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5909cd61bb53d1af658864e8", "question": "How old was Kevin in the 1990 film \"Home Alone\"?", "answer": "8 years old", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a710", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Magnolia State\"?", "answer": "Mississippi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad59", "question": "For what purpose did George Washington Carver originally encourage farmers to grow peanuts?", "answer": "Crop rotation", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca70", "question": "What kind of animal was the now extinct Dodo?", "answer": "Bird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8aa1c01dd7bf43be5e757", "question": "What is the Hebrew term for \"commandment\"?", "answer": "Mitzvah", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab8d", "question": "What country shares a border with Cambodia to the northwest?", "answer": "Thailand", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a563", "question": "Staten Island is part of what city?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdc15c4469bb8041d07a08c", "question": "What does \"dim sum\" mean in English?", "answer": "Touching heart", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febb25e7e83c707845b2111", "question": "What founding father also founded the University of Pennsylvania?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac95", "question": "How did the founder of Vassar College accumulate his wealth?", "answer": "He was a brewer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe3ee638b5801b8f54a7fb7", "question": "Which was the last major offensive operation undertaken by elite German paratroopers in World War II?", "answer": "Attack against Crete", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac8e", "question": "What is the practical purpose of the Pharos of Alexandria?", "answer": "Lighthouse", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0f4", "question": "How many points did the Dow drop on \"Black Monday\" in 1987?", "answer": "508", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f06", "question": "What author created the character of Nero Wolfe?", "answer": "Rex Stout", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5909ce91bb53d1af658864f1", "question": "In the song \"The Twelve Days of Christmas\", what type of tree did the Partridge come in?", "answer": "Pear tree", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe65c321f3c0ead6880d60f", "question": "What weapon dominated the Battle of Agincourt?", "answer": "Longbow", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390e1", "question": "What year was Ben Jonson's \"The Alchemist\" first performed?", "answer": "1610", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa41fbc73aa70ea0b70b12", "question": "Which port city was the first capital of Pakistan?", "answer": "Karachi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9f1", "question": "What is the fear of social situations called?", "answer": "Sociophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a5f", "question": "What actor's character ran \"Blush\" magazine on the TV show \"Just Shoot Me\"?", "answer": "George Segal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f22801dd7bf43be5e80d", "question": "What do skydivers traditionally do for their 100th jump?", "answer": "They skydive nude", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3da444f0f6af5b06663d", "question": "In which Dickens novel does the character Fezziwigs appear?", "answer": "A Christmas Carol", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6df", "question": "Who collaborated with Beno Gutenburg to devise a system of measuring the intensity of earthquakes?", "answer": "Charles Richter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "594d06551a1c922dd1ac64aa", "question": "What nation has had its own scandals dubbed \"Muldergate\" and \"Inkathagate\"?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fa2", "question": "A story of ones own life is referred to as what?", "answer": "Autobiography", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339202", "question": "What do Brad Pitt and Edward Norton shoot at factories while drunk in \"Fight Club\"?", "answer": "Golf Balls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab187ebaab681b0929218a", "question": "Which company introduced the Mangusta in the 1960\u2019s?", "answer": "De Tomaso", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb0c", "question": "What science-fiction author founded the Church of Scientology in 1953?", "answer": "L. Ron Hubbard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfdc", "question": "What sport did Andre Agassi's dad compete in?", "answer": "Boxing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae4b", "question": "Who did Harry Truman dismiss as commander of the UN forces in Korea in 1951?", "answer": "General Douglas MacArthur", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ad", "question": "Who recorded the international hit single \"Poker Face\" in 2008?", "answer": "Lady Gaga", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad35", "question": "Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. received his Ph.D. from which school?", "answer": "Boston University", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0e4", "question": "Which pasta is shaped like a short tube?", "answer": "Ditalini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab1177baab681b0929216c", "question": "In The Flintstones, what is the name of Barney Rubble's pet?", "answer": "Hoppy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecdb5fec223966ae8f88f4", "question": "What movie marked the Hollywood film debut of William Shatner?", "answer": "\"The Brothers Karamazov\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008d29cf842fa4c4ba96a7", "question": "If you suffer from diplopia, what do you have?", "answer": "Double vision", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff66f4952a821ff76ae8b1e", "question": "In Skamania County, Washington, it\u2019s illegal to kill what creature?", "answer": "Bigfoot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c71a", "question": "What planet's four largest moons are collectively known as the Galilean Moons?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "592eaf1cf83302ff91e46490", "question": "What city was nicknamed \"The Paris of the West\"?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd55", "question": "The Patsy Award is an award given in what field?", "answer": "Animal acting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e4", "question": "Whose memory is the movie \"Gladiator\" dedicated to?", "answer": "Oliver Reed's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c81d", "question": "Starfish belong to what animal phylum, whose name means \"spiny skin\"?", "answer": "Echinoderms", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339752", "question": "What was the first silent movie to win the Best Picture Oscar?", "answer": "Wings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe93a6f6bd93ce3a4e5f697", "question": "Who is \"the Science Guy\"?", "answer": "Bill Nye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac2a", "question": "Which German federal state surrounds the city-state of Berlin?", "answer": "Brandenburg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba9c", "question": "What are the six weapons in a standard game of Clue?", "answer": "Candlestick, Lead Pipe, Knife, Revolver, Rope, and aWrench", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac5d", "question": "What shortage killed over one million Irish people in the 1840s?", "answer": "Potatoes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339307", "question": "What is Dr. Hannibal Lector's profession?", "answer": "Psychiatrist", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8c1", "question": "Coq au vin is a dish made with which type of meat?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338995", "question": "Who was married to Andrew Lloyd Webber when he composed \"The Phantom of the Opera\" for her voice?", "answer": "Sarah Brightman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a721", "question": "The resort town of Avalon is situated on what California island?", "answer": "Santa Catalina Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd66bf8a5bfecdd737e088c", "question": "What was the original name of Vaseline?", "answer": "Wonder jelly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2cfb42596a59cbdfbd372", "question": "Who said, \u201cStrong minds discuss ideas, average minds discuss events, weak minds discuss people\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5937ecd808d98002fdd633c1", "question": "What is an Ishihara Test used for?", "answer": "To check colour blindness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339529", "question": "Who won an Academy Award for her role as Lisa Rowe in the 1999 movie \"Girl, Interrupted\"?", "answer": "Angelina Jolie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b756", "question": "What team did basketball star Larry Bird play 13 seasons for?", "answer": "Boston Celtics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a304", "question": "What was singer George Jones' animal nickname?", "answer": "The Possum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea37fbff048f679a45ab1f", "question": "Which psychological concept did Pavlov\u2019s dog help him describe?", "answer": "Conditioning", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a38e", "question": "What is the only officially bilingual province in Canada?", "answer": "New Brunswick", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefc3dd6ce05a3942286f28", "question": "Which member of Fleetwood Mac was inducted into the Rock & Roll Hall of Fame twice?", "answer": "Stevie Nicks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e66", "question": "When subjects of \"Who's Who\" pass away, what companion volume do they move to?", "answer": "Who Was Who", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c20e", "question": "Which country hosted the 1924 Summer and Winter Olympic Games?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e57", "question": "What word for a series of dots is a top secret code word in the Bond film \"Casino Royale\"?", "answer": "Ellipsis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec261b8dc25ca9e12ef646", "question": "Which country traditionally gives London's Trafalgar Square its Christmas tree?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a9e930f7ccba3ffe45786c1", "question": "What year did Stella Gibbons publish the novel \"Cold Comfort Farm\"?", "answer": "1932", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec8d25ec223966ae8f884f", "question": "Who said this in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"? \"Hope is a dangerous thing. Hope can drive a man insane.\"", "answer": "Red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7e20ff048f679a45ac07", "question": "Atelophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Imperfection", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133919d", "question": "Who was the voice of Donkey in the \"Shrek\" movie series?", "answer": "Eddie Murphy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed0", "question": "What game of chance was originally called \"Beano\"?", "answer": "Bingo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391d5", "question": "Which band is known in Spain as U-Dos?", "answer": "U2", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b218", "question": "Who was assassinated by Giuseppe Zangara?", "answer": "Anton Cermak", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fed2b94ec223966ae8f890e", "question": "What film bankrupted Carolco Pictures?", "answer": "\"Cutthroat Island\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339563", "question": "Bill Melendez directed which Christmas TV special?", "answer": "A Charlie Brown Christmas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d78", "question": "What movie features three tunnels named Tom, Dick, and Harry?", "answer": "The Great Escape", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afe1", "question": "For what crime was Susan B. Anthony arrested in 1872?", "answer": "Voting", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b237", "question": "May Day, as an international workers' celebration, dates back to what 1886 event?", "answer": "The Haymarket labor riot", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4c7c49076251badbead5", "question": "Which newspaper incorrectly reported Thomas E. Dewey defeated Harry S. Truman in the 1948 U.S. Presidential Election?", "answer": "Chicago Daily Tribune -- Now known as Chicago Tribune, it had once referred to Truman as a \"nincompoop\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fc9914375534e0fe3fe3c29", "question": "Who said, \"Love is a serious mental disease\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b3ade662d71a53650fe1", "question": "What unique quirk did Fr\u00e9d\u00e9ric Chopin have?", "answer": "He preferred to play in the dark.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b805", "question": "In the clothing store name \"L. L. Bean\", what do the letters \"L\" stand for?", "answer": "Leon Leonwood", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4e3", "question": "What letter appears on the left end of the bottom letter row of a traditional QWERTY keyboard?", "answer": "The letter Z", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ea", "question": "The music band \"The Cardigans\" hail from what European country?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396de", "question": "Which pop group was initially named \"The Pendletones\"?", "answer": "The Beach Boys", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0b8", "question": "To protest an unpopular tax, which US state's residents held the \"Whiskey Rebellion\" in 1794?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba0d", "question": "What fast food chain was founded by Colonel Harland Sanders?", "answer": "Kentucky Fried Chicken", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010ca1f0775fa611bce67f3", "question": "What Apple computer was named after Steve Jobs' daughter?", "answer": "Lisa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f3c", "question": "What two American leading men are related to director Francis Ford Coppola?", "answer": "Nicolas Cage and Jason Schwartzman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe658b7ae7e414034b5aef6", "question": "Who were the two leaders of Chile's Independence movement from 1810 until 1818?", "answer": "Bernardo O'Higgins And Jose De San Martin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b7e", "question": "Who played Lex Luthor in the 2006 film \"Superman Returns\"?", "answer": "Kevin Spacey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f43", "question": "What future \"Cheers\" star plays Mob boss Tommy Como in \"Raging Bull\"?", "answer": "Nicholas \"Coach\" Colasanto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66942a5bfecdd737e0879", "question": "Why do Italians eat lentils on New Year's Eve?", "answer": "To bring good fortune", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febac517e83c707845b20ec", "question": "What is the scientific name of the \"western lowland gorilla\"?", "answer": "Gorilla gorilla gorilla", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c04c", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Belarus?", "answer": "White stork", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133988d", "question": "Which South African femal singer was known as Mama Africa?", "answer": "Miriam Makeba", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8b7", "question": "How many strings are there on a standard violin?", "answer": "4", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a05720565ad31a57c794", "question": "What historical ruler instituted one of the first international postal services?", "answer": "Genghis Khan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2f2", "question": "What is the international radio code word for the letter T?", "answer": "Tango", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe65c701f3c0ead6880d615", "question": "What did the 1928 Kellogg-Briand Pact, signed by 62 nations, denounce?", "answer": "War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9b9", "question": "The zodiac sign \"Cancer\" refers to what animal?", "answer": "Crab", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca81", "question": "From what animal fat was margarine first made from in the US?", "answer": "Beef", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015fd0afe83fe1f2a824c49", "question": "Which personality in the Bible got blinded by a bright light on his way to Damascus?", "answer": "Saul", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf1a", "question": "What is the colour of mourning in Turkey?", "answer": "Violet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b554", "question": "In rugby, what is the equivalent of a hockey face-off?", "answer": "Scrum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7bec1877e98cb97778963", "question": "What is the fastest flowing river in the world?", "answer": "Amazon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febd7947e83c707845b2173", "question": "What popular movie musical, directed by John Huston, was released in 1982?", "answer": "\"Annie\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a737", "question": "Which US state is home to Craters of the Moon National Monument?", "answer": "Idaho", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133936f", "question": "What zodiac sign is the Joker in the movie \"Batman\"?", "answer": "Pisces", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febda227e83c707845b2181", "question": "Which American golfer was nicknamed \"The Joplin Ghost\"?", "answer": "Horton Smith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abc7", "question": "What is the capital of South Africa?", "answer": "Pretoria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ae92ec574a5ce6b56b8233", "question": "What sport is played by the Chicago Bulls?", "answer": "Basketball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf2a", "question": "A spice from which root is used to give food a yellow colour?", "answer": "Turmeric", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d4f", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"THX 1138\"?", "answer": "Maggie McOmie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af259acb63e5727cf5a4851", "question": "Which rock band released the singles \"Karma Police\" and \"Creep\"?", "answer": "Radiohead", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5a3f6ce05a3942286e0b", "question": "\"Life is Beautiful\" has been named one of the top-five favorite films of which prominent figure?", "answer": "Pope John Paul II", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ec0e08d98002fdd633b6", "question": "Which singer wrote the autobiography \"Take It Like a Man\"?", "answer": "Boy George", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015dfa4fe83fe1f2a824b7c", "question": "What queen defeated and killed Cyrus the Great of Persia?", "answer": "Tomyris", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c101", "question": "What is the official language of Austria?", "answer": "German", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bec7", "question": "What does a Collier do?", "answer": "Makes charcoal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8db", "question": "Who won a record eight gold medals at the 2008 Summer Olympics in Beijing?", "answer": "Michael Phelps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad22", "question": "What year did the Three Mile Island accident occur?", "answer": "1979", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c89e24011619dd6d41548b", "question": "In season 16 of South Park, what chain store did Randy buy for $10,000?", "answer": "Blockbuster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f4f301dd7bf43be5e826", "question": "What is the point at which two lines meet to form an angle?", "answer": "Vertex", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe93bce6bd93ce3a4e5f6a6", "question": "Percentage-wise, how big were the brains of the extinct species Australopithecus compared to a modern human brain?", "answer": "35%", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae19", "question": "In which decade did Hawaii become a state?", "answer": "1950s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "596dfe159616e6c6d4eba4fb", "question": "What island does the Statue of Liberty stand on?", "answer": "Liberty Island", "category": "general"}, {"id": "591c34e9815febcc896f9257", "question": "What continent is Sao Tome and Principe located in?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffcfbe89dc5ec6cd98a8319", "question": "Who painted The Son of Man?", "answer": "Ren\u00e9 Magritte (The surrealist intended\u00a0the painting\u00a0of a man whose face is obscured by a hovering green apple as a self-portrait.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015f8d0fe83fe1f2a824c2f", "question": "Who are the first people known to have consumed chocolate?", "answer": "Olmecs. There is evidence that the ancient Olmecs of what is now Mexico consumed chocolate beverages as far back as 1900 BC", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffb61365dad637d903c882e", "question": "What is the smallest country in South America?", "answer": "Suriname", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe0db79fcbed638185eaa09", "question": "What is the smallest country by square mileage in North America?", "answer": "St. Kitts & Nevis", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4b3ba06d333868d34d6dc", "question": "In what year did the Korean War end?", "answer": "Although hostilities ended in 1953, there was never a formal peace treaty as of 2020", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b28", "question": "Who wrote \"The Murders in the Rue Morgue\"?", "answer": "Edgar Allan Poe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0aebde662d71a53650fbb", "question": "What was Bram Stoker's original name for Dracula?", "answer": "Count Wampyr", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c829fbde8045e48466d1", "question": "The Horsehead Nebula can be found in what constellation?", "answer": "Orion", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59008a56cf842fa4c4ba968f", "question": "What nationality was Johnny Weissmuller?", "answer": "Hungarian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf9", "question": "What year did Edward Jenner introduce the world's first successful vaccine?", "answer": "1796", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b294", "question": "What president proposed the Great Society?", "answer": "Lyndon Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bddf", "question": "What's the common household name for diluted acetic acid?", "answer": "Vinegar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eff", "question": "What famous horse belonged to Dudley Do-Right?", "answer": "Horse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb8c", "question": "How many total combined red and black numbers are there on a roulette wheel?", "answer": "36", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a856", "question": "Which building houses the world's biggest four-faced chiming clock?", "answer": "Minneapolis City Hall", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59068076ff9c0647b50a808c", "question": "At what age did Prince release his debut album \"For You\"?", "answer": "19", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9cc", "question": "What is another term for the sternum?", "answer": "Breastbone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc3f", "question": "Tennis player Rafael Nadal goes by what nickname?", "answer": "Rafa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a1e1e78b5a031299b745740", "question": "What year did Great Britain claim the eastern half of Australia?", "answer": "1770", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396df", "question": "In which country was Nicole Kidman born?", "answer": "United States", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef93396ce05a3942286e8b", "question": "Frank Darabont seriously contemplated selling the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\" script to which person?", "answer": "Rob Reiner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59049d99cf93664eb10486af", "question": "The plane carrying what country\u2019s national rugby team crashed on Friday, October 13, 1972?", "answer": "Uruguay\u2019s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aba6", "question": "What is the capital of Wyoming?", "answer": "Cheyenne", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc1abec223966ae8f886c", "question": "Makeup artist Joanna Balkin says she needed 40 bottles of sunscreen per month to protect what 1990s TV show\u2019s cast from sunburns?", "answer": "\"Baywatch\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea31c0ff048f679a45aae4", "question": "What is the most common form of stalactites?", "answer": "Speleothems", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c326", "question": "The zero of which two temperature scales is known as \"Absolute Zero\"?", "answer": "Kelvin and Rankine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea7e77ff048f679a45ac0f", "question": "Batrachophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Amphibians", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd96c6b23c87fd04dd15e24", "question": "What instrument did Paul McCartney primarily play as a member of the Beatles?", "answer": "Bass", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4f7", "question": "What is the street address of the White House?", "answer": "1600 Pennsylvania Avenue", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab0fd0baab681b0929216a", "question": "Valentine's Day is also known as the \"Feast of...\" what?", "answer": "Saint Valentine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4a6f49076251badbeab5", "question": "In 1912, what company introduced the first \"cash and carry\" grocery chain, which moved away from traditional delivery?", "answer": "A & P", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef5b666ce05a3942286e15", "question": "Which actress was the first American to win a Ca\u00e9sar, the French equivalent Oscar, in 2015?", "answer": "Kristen Stewart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5aab2f9058d116dab4aecb4b", "question": "What's the name of the technique for collecting measurements at a distance?", "answer": "Telemetry", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a598", "question": "What part of New York city got its name because it lies south of Houston Street?", "answer": "SoHo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe65813ae7e414034b5aee6", "question": "What tragedy took place on April 15, 1912?", "answer": "The Titanic sank", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b598e662d71a53650ffc", "question": "Philip Pirrip is the main protagonist in which work by Charles Dickens?", "answer": "\"Great Expectations\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc262ec223966ae8f8874", "question": "What movie star uses his middle initial, B, for \"Bakari\", to avoid confusion with a retired basketball star?", "answer": "Michael B. Jordan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a24", "question": "What European capital city was the setting for the musical \"Cabaret\"?", "answer": "Berlin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a6c", "question": "Who was elected as leader of the boys at the beginning of the novel \"Lord of the Flies\"?", "answer": "Ralph", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd96", "question": "What British comedian refers to himself as an \"executive transvestite\"?", "answer": "Eddie Izzard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a9ec20565ad31a57c80d", "question": "The Nazi organization NSDAP stands for what?", "answer": "National German Workers' Party (Nationalsozialistische Deutsche Arbeiterparteiz)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397cf", "question": "Who recorded the 1955 song \"Ain't That a Shame\"?", "answer": "Fats Domino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9dcfae748bb36357acddf", "question": "In the original \"Oregon Trail\" game, made in 1971, what were the four infectious diseases that could kill members of your party?", "answer": "Typhoid, Cholera, Measles, Dysentery", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd96b5423c87fd04dd15e1a", "question": "1816 was known as the year without what?", "answer": "Summer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dec", "question": "What was the name of Paul Winchell's dummy?", "answer": "Jerry Mahoney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c8c7877e98cb977789ec", "question": "Where is the Sphinx Observatory located?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600cc0666de0eb824d4052d9", "question": "What is the most populous city in Australia?", "answer": "Sidney", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b1a", "question": "Who is Mary Shelley's most famous scientist character?", "answer": "Dr. Frankenstein", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c72b", "question": "What organ in the human body produces insulin?", "answer": "Pancreas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c94a", "question": "What is the fear of getting wrinkles known as?", "answer": "Rhytiphobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f566fa33a95c66dc4fe767", "question": "Who directed the 1941 film \"Citizen Kane\"?", "answer": "Orson Welles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ef2108d98002fdd633de", "question": "When is the only time a flag should be flown upside down?", "answer": "Emergency", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6aa7020565ad31a57c818", "question": "What was the name of the airplane that Charles Lindbergh used to make his famous solo flight across the Atlantic Ocean?", "answer": "The Spirit of St Louis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f8", "question": "Who released an album called \"Ghost in the Machine\"?", "answer": "The Police", "category": "entertainment"}]